<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://friesbusinessreview.com</id>
    <title>FIRESBUSINESSREVIEW</title>
    <updated>2021-05-09T09:46:59.046Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://friesbusinessreview.com"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://friesbusinessreview.com/atom.xml"/>
    <logo>https://friesbusinessreview.com/images/avatar.png</logo>
    <icon>https://friesbusinessreview.com/favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>All rights reserved 2021, FIRESBUSINESSREVIEW</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[📒Internship Journal]]></title>
        <id>https://friesbusinessreview.com/post/about/</id>
        <link href="https://friesbusinessreview.com/post/about/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-05-09T09:16:54.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>##Day 1</p>
<ul>
<li>Visit private bank room + Join a regular meeting</li>
<li>Read PPT (&quot;Shenzhen Branch bank course,&quot; &quot;Introduction of products independently developed by private bank,&quot; &quot;Operation practice of private bank&quot;, Caizhihui)</li>
<li>Read &quot;Wealth Consultant&quot;（《财富顾问》） -&gt; Post qualification certification examination series teaching material</li>
<li>Wang Xing always thinks that finance is divided into three levels: banks -&gt; securities companies/fund companies -&gt; investment banks; Suggest me to take the CFA test</li>
<li>China Merchants Bank has done well in facing young people, while ABC traditionally focuses on rural areas, so urban ABCs (eg. Shenzhen has no rural areas) faces a difficult situation</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>⚠️Tips:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Understand the concept: I said I have some understanding of the fund, such as the concept of retracement, Wang Xing asked me its definition but I could not respond clearly, saying that it was a loss of money...(in fact it's the magnitude of the fluctuation)</li>
<li>Close the door after everyone when you arrive at the regular meeting</li>
<li>Bring cell phone with me in case I need to add others' WeChat (I forgot it when I went to see the boss)</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>⏰Tasks after class:</strong><br>
<strong>Wang:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>What is a fund like learning</li>
<li>Household asset allocation reports</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Liu:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Financial Intelligence Publicity Program</li>
<li>Marketing hot spots in the next four months</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Tomorrow:</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Remember to bring a pillow</li>
<li>Check  news on apps everyday</li>
</ol>
<p>##Day 2</p>
<ul>
<li>Learn Excel: VLOOKUP (match data) &amp; PivotTable (compare and analyze)</li>
<li>There's a &quot;Party Building&quot; activity today, stuffs from each branch bank came to perform and make speech</li>
<li>Learn about stock and fund (read books &amp; make mindmap)</li>
<li>Modify the advertisement of &quot;Caizhihui,&quot; which will be sent through Wechat Official Account tomorrow</li>
<li>There is a good design company called &quot;Start-up Salad.&quot;</li>
</ul>
<p>⚠️Tips</p>
<ul>
<li>company culture: Weekly 3-mile run + send picture to the group chat.</li>
<li>I forgot to bring my ID card and converter again!</li>
</ul>
<p>##Day 3</p>
<ul>
<li>Morning: Met Client with Mrs. Na (who does trust) at Longgang. She is about 40, works in Pingan insurance, has a son. Her husband works in PE. She doesn't really want to buy trust but more about learning it as a a person of the same trade or business (Mrs. Na told me later and said she realized this soon). They discussed about their children first (three people: Mrs. Na, the Client Mrs. Liu, and the head of this brank bank Mrs. Wu, all of which have a child in high school). I find it really interesting because in China many discussion start with children. Mrs. Na said in China <strong>Family trust</strong> really started in 2018.
<ul>
<li>Wealth management may be a good future career choice.</li>
<li>Tea &amp; jewelry are popular topics in China.</li>
<li>Many senior executives tend to avoid chosing the finance products of their own companies for** [privacy]**❕</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Discussed Fund with Wang and was assigned new topics (the difference between private and public offering funds; automatic investment plan)</li>
<li>Got my fund account, which means I can really buy my 1st fund next week! (😄my first step towards investment coming SOON!)</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>